Charity Cannon Willard Papers, 1891-2006
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES IV. LECTURES AND CONFERENCE PAPERS
  - Popular
    - "The French in the New World" (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - "The Royal Palace of Sintra" (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - "The Mechanical Clock" (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - "Sylvanus Thayer of West Point" (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - "In the Company of Educated Women" (to the Cornwall-on-the-Hudson Reading Club) (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - "Portuguese Immigrants" (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - "Life in Forts Along the Frontiers" (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Lecture programs, fliers, and miscellaneous papers
    - "Christine de Pisan: The World's First Voice for Women's Rights (1364-1430)" lecture flier. The College at New Paltz, State University of New York: April 30. (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Sewanee Medieval Colloquium Program - 1987 (2 copies) (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - The World of St. Paul: Judaism, Christianity, and Greco-Roman Civilization pamphlet. Harvard Alumni Association: November 10-22, 2002. (Box 1, Folder 80)
- SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES: CHRISTINE DE PIZAN, [See also SERIES VII. OVERSIZED MATERIALS]]
  - Photocopies of manuscripts, books, etc.
    - Solente, Suzanne. "Christine de Pizan." Paris: Imprimerie Nationale, 1969. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Salet, Frances and Erlande-Brandenburg, Alain. "La Priorale Saint-Louis de Poissy." Bulletin Monumental. Paris: Musée des Monuments Français, Société Française d'Archéologie, 1971. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Dulac, Liliane, ed. Pizan, Christine. "Heures de Contemplacion sur la Passion de Nostre Seigneur" MS of Paris, B.N., n.a. fr. 10059, fol. 114-144 with changes made from the MS of La Hague, B. Royale, 73. J. 55, fol. 51-92v. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "MS 8 Christine de Pizan, Epitre d'Othéa" (article with examples of manuscript and notes). (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Le Roman de Florimont" MS 125266 (typed manuscript). (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Pizan, Christine. "Les Heures de Contemplacion sur la Passion de Nostre Seigneur (dialecte de l'Est)" (typed manuscript). (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Pizan, Christine. "Le Livre des Faits d'Armes et de Chevalerie" (partial photocopied manuscript). (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - "La Prud'homme de l'Omme" (typed manuscript) (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Pizan, Christine. "La Fleur de Toutes Vertus." Paris, B.N.F., MS fo. 24.785. (photocopied manuscript) (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Pizan, Christine. "Le Livre des Trois Vertus." (photocopied manuscript) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Pizan, Christine. "Le Livre des Trois Vertus." Boston Public Library, MS 1528. (photocopied manuscript) (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Pizan, Christine. "Le Livre des Trois Vertus." Brussels, Bibl. Roy., MS 0973. (photocopied manuscript) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Pizan, Christine. "Le Livre des Trois Vertus." Paris, B.N.F., MS fo. 25.294. (photocopied manuscript) (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Pizan, Christine. "Le Livre des Trois Vertus." Paris, B.N.F., MS fo. 452. (photocopied manuscript). (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Unidentified photocopied manuscript (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Misc. photocopied manuscript pages (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - List of Christine de Pizan manuscripts (Box 2, Folder 17)
- SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES: CHRISTINE DE PIZAN
  - Articles by colleagues
    - "Biographie de Jean de Mantagu, Grand Maître de France" Bibliothèque de l'École des chartes XIII. 1852. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - "The Anglo-French Negotiations, 1439." Bulletin of the Institute of Historical Research, Vol. XL, No. 101. May 1967. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - "Beaux Livres Anciens et Modernes." Librairie Lardanecht, 1976. 35-41. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Reno, Christine M. and Ouy, Gilbert. "Identification des Autographes de de Pizan." Scriptorium: International Review of Manuscript Studies. Tome XXXIV. Gand: E. Story-Scientia S.P.R.L., 1980. (with offprint) (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - "Guardian Women" 1 June 1984. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Schneider-Lastin, Wolfram. "Hanschriftenfunde zur Literatur des Mittelalters: Christine de Pizan Deutsch." Zeitschrift für deutsches Altertum und deutsche Literatur (ZFDA). 125:2, 1996. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - "The Christine de Pizan Society Newsletter." 9 March 1999. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Walters, Lori J. "The Royal Vernacular: Poet and Patron in Christine de Pizan's Charles V and the Sept Psaumes Allégorisés." Blumenfeld-Kosinski, Renate; Robertson, Duncan; and Warren, Nancy Bradley, eds. The Vernacular Spirit: Essays on Medieval Religious Literature. New York: Palgrave, 2002. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Parussa, Gabriella. "Veior, Oïr et Entendre l'Epistre Othéa et le Cycle Iconographique de Deux Manuscrits." Favola, Mito ed Altrisaggi di Letteratura e Filologia. 2003. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - "Christine de Pizan: Une Femme de Science, Une femme de lettres: Résumés" Colloque international: Université de Liége. 11-15 January 2005. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - "Bibliographie: A propos d'un livre récent sur Christine de Pizan." (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Thomas, A. "Jean Castel." Romania XXI. 1982. 271-74 (with notes) (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Reno, Christine M. "The Cursive and Calligraphic Scripts of Christine de Pizan." (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Richards, Earl Jeffrey. "Christine de Pizan and Jean Gerson." (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - "Notice sur la Construction du Palais Rihour à Lille" (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - ==Offprints by colleagues
    - Mombello, Gianni. "Recherches sur l'Origine du Nom de la Déesse Othéa." Dagli, Estratto. Atti Della Academia delle Scienze di Torino. Vol. 103. 1968-69. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Mombello, Gianni. "Quelques aspects de la pensée politique de Christine de Pizan d'après ses œuvres publiées." Dagli, Estratto. Tai del Convegno su: 'Culture et politique en France à l'époque de l'Humanisme et de la Renaissance.' Academia delle Scienze di Torino. 29 March - 3 April, 1971. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Bernard, Paul R., ed. Les Bonnes Feuilles: Special Edition: Christine de Pizan. Vol. III, No. ii. Pennsylvania State University, Fall 1974. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Kennedy, Angus. "La Lamentation sur les maux de la France de Christine de Pizan." Foulon, Charles. Mélanges de Langue et Littérature Françaises de Moyen Age et de la Renaissance. Tome I. Institut de Français, Université de Haute Bretagne, 1980. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Dulac, Liliane. "Dissymétrie et échec de la communication dans les Cent Balades d'Amant et de Dame de Christine de Pizan." Lengas: Dix Années de Sociolinguistique / Détz ans de Sociolingüística. Montpellier, 1987. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Kennedy, Angus. "Le manuscrit de Châtellerault. Un manuscrit perdu du VIIe livre de 'La Mutacion de Fortune.'" Zimmerman, Margarete and De Rentiis, Dina. The City of Scholars: New Approaches to Christine de Pizan. Berlin: Walter de Gruyter, 1994. (2 copies) (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Fenster, Thelma. "Review of The City of Scholars: New Approaches to Christine de Pizan edited by Margarete Zimmerman and Dina de Rentiis." Speculum 72.2 (1997). (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Smith, Geri L. "Christine de Pizan's Dit de la Pasteure - A Feminization of the Pastourelle." Romance Notes. Vol. XXXIX, No. 3. 1999. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Smith, Geri L. "De Marotele au Lai Mortel: La Subversion Discursive du Code Courtois Dans Deux Ouvrages de Christine de Pizan." Hicks, Eric. Au Champ des Escriptures, III Colloque international sur Christine de Pizan. Paris: Honoré Champion Éditeur, 2000. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Walters, Loris J. "Autobiographie et Humanisme: la Réception de Pétrarque par Christine de Pizan." Dynamique d'une expansion culturelle Pétrarque en Europe XIV-XX Siècle. Paris: Honoré Champion Éditeur, 2001. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Altman, Barbara. "L'Art de l'Autoportrait Littéraire dans les Cent Ballades de Christine de Pizan." (Box 2, Folder 33)
- SERIES VI. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS
  - Photographs
    - Photographed manuscript: Christine de Pisan, Lettre à Isabelle de Bavière, reine de France. Flandre méridionale ou France, c. 1490. MS. IV 1176 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Brussels, Bibliothèque Royale. MS. 1. Les Grandes Chroniques de France. f. 170. Le Château de Poissy. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Brussels, Bibliothèque Royale. MS. 10387, f. 1. (2 copies) (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - London, British Library. MS. 3921, f. 51. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Postcard: London, British Library. Harley MS. 4431, f. 81. "Riding Party" (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - London, British Library. Harley MS. 4431, f. 221, 3346. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Lyon, Bibliothèque de la ville de Lyon. 240 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Paris, Bibliothèque nationale de France. 12994 MS. Fr. 948, f. 1. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Paris, Bibliothèque nationale de France. 12994 MS. Fr. 948, f. 14. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Paris, Bibliothèque nationale de France. 12994 MS. Fr. 948, f. 184. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Paris, Bibliothèque nationale de France. 12994 MS. Fr. 2807, f. 12. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Paris, Bibliothèque nationale de France. 30648 MS. Fr. 948, f. IIV (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Miscellaneous other photographs (one of a scribe's signature, 12 of an unidentified page of text) (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Slides
    - L'époque de Charles VI from Les Trésors de la Bibliothèque Nationale: Département des Manuscrits. Commentaires par Marcel Thomas. Éditions Filmées d'Art et d'Histoire. 1957. (20-slide collection with commentary book) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Adoration (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Adoration (on manuscript page) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Adoration of the Magi (after van Eyck) - 88. MS. 868 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Annunciation to Shepherds - 87. MS. 868 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Bibliothèque publique et universitaire. A. Steinschaber (1478). Jean d'Arras. Mélusine. Genève. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Bibliothèque publique et universitaire. Attribué à Jean Perrissin (vers 1530-vers 1611). Temple de Lyon, nommé Paradis. Vers 1565. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Bologna, Pinacoteca nazionale. Jacopo da Bologna. Politico. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Bologna, Pinacoteca nazionale. The Virgin's coronation (Le Couronnement de la Vierge). (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Catherine of Clèves Kneeling - Virgin and Child (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Virgin and Child - 124. MS. 358 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Seated Virgin and Child - 125. MS. 358 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Holy Family at Supper (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Mary the Virgin: Marriage - MS. 453 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Mary the Virgin weaving - 37. MS. 453 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Nativity - 86. MS. 868 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - MS. 212, f. 1 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - MS. 213, f. 1 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous (16 slides) (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Microfilm
    - Armand M. Queyroy, Enseignements d'Anne de France à sa fille Susanne de Bourbon. Moulins: C. Desrosiers, 1878. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Boston, Boston Public Library. MS. 1528. Christine de Pizan, Le Livre des Trois Vertus. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Brussels, Bibliothèque Royale. MS. 1093. Christine de Pizan, Les sept psaumes allégorisés (Louis de Bruges.) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Brussels, Bibliothèque Royale. MS. 9009-9011. Christine de Pizan, Le livre des fais d'armes et de chevalerie. (Croy ) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Brussels, Bibliothèque Royale. MS. 9235, 10973-74. Christine de Pizan, La cité des dames - Le Livre des Trois Vertus (en A). (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Brussels, Bibliothèque Royale. MS. 9551-52. Christine de Pizan, Le Livre des Trois Vertus. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Brussels, Bibliothèque Royale. MS. 10205. Christine de Pizan, Le livre des fais d'armes et de chevalerie. (Box 3, Folder 7a)
    - Brussels, Bibliothèque Royale. MS. 10205. Christine de Pizan, Le livre des fais d'armes et de chevalerie. (Box 3, Folder 7b)
    - Brussels, Bibliothèque Royale. MS. 10476. Christine de Pizan, Le livre des fais d'armes et de chevalerie. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Brussels, Bibliothèque Royale. MS. 11048. Vegesce [Vegetius], Le livre de l'art de chevalerie. *Note: Wound backwards (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Chantilly, Musée Condé. MS. 492. Cent Ballades - Dit de la pastoure (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Dresden, Sächsische Landesbibliothek. MS. 770. Le Livre des Trois Vertus. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - The Hague, Royal Library. MS. 71 E 46. Philippe de Clèves, Art de Guerroyer. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - The Hague, Royal Library. MS. 131 C 26. Christine de Pizan, Le Livre des Trois Vertus. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Lille, Bibliothèque Municipale. Godetroy 50. Histoire de Gilles de Chin. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Lille, Bibliothèque Municipale. Godetroy 152. Christine de Pizan, Le Livre des Trois Vertus. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Lille, Bibliothèque Municipale. MS. 607. Vacotin de Ramecourt, Spiritual Texts Copied for Isabel du Portugal. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - London, British Library. MS. 1073.A.4. Christine de Pizan, Le chemin de long estude. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - London, British Library. Add. 15641. Christine de Pizan, Le Livre des Trois Vertus. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - London, British Library. Add. 21370. Correspondence of [Jean de Verchin] Seneschal of Hainault, with Henry IV of England, Sir John Cornwall and others, (Cartes et Debris d'Armes) (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - London, British Library. Harley 219. Christine de Pizan, L'Épître d'Othéa. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - London, British Library. Harley 4431. Christine de Pizan, Poésies. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - London, British Library. Harley 4605. Christine de Pizan. Des fais d'armes. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - London, British Library. Ps. MS. 907. Lansdowne. 214. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Oxford, Bodleian Library. MS. 7423. Christine de Pizan, Le Livre des Trois Vertus. (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Paris, Bibliothèque de l'Arsenal. 3356 no. 1-264. 1. Le Chevalier de la Tour Landry 2. Christine de Pizan, Le Livre des Trois Vertus (129). (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Paris, Bibliothèque nationale de France. Fr. 214, No. 1 - 68. R. 16.413. Livre des faits de Boucicaut. (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Paris, Bibliothèque nationale de France. Fr. 301. No. 1-295. R. 10.735. Histoire ancienne jusqu'à César. (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Paris, Bibliothèque nationale de France. Fr. 452; Fr. 1177. Christine de Pizan, Le Livre des Trois Vertus. (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Paris, Bibliothèque nationale de France. Fr. 585. Le livre des fais d'armes et de chevalerie. (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Paris, Bibliothèque nationale de France. Fr. 605-607, 1197. Christine de Pizan, Livre de prudence, Le corp de Policie. (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Paris, Bibliothèque nationale de France. Fr. 835. Christine de Pizan, Épîtres sur le roman de la rose. (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Paris, Bibliothèque nationale de France. Fr. 1091. L. Du Premier fait, Livre des 4 vertus. Christine de Pizan, Livre des Trois Vertus. (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Paris, Bibliothèque nationale de France. Fr. 1180. Le Livre des Trois Vertus. (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Paris, Bibliothèque nationale de France. Fr. 12779. Oeuvres de Christine Pizan (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Paris, Bibliothèque nationale de France. Fr. 24786. L'Epistre de la Prison de Vie Humaine. Fr. 24864 - Lamentation sur la Guerre Civile. (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Paris, Bibliothèque nationale de France. Rés. 611. Vérard ed. Le livre des fais d'armes et de chevalerie. (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Paris, Bibliothèque nationale de France. Res. 42 2073. Christine de Pizan, Trésor de la cité des dames. (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Paris, Bibliothèque nationale de France. Res. Y2 186. R. 1864. Christine de Pizan. Le Trésor de la cité des dames. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Paris, Bibliothèque nationale de France. R. Sh. 613, cod. 18.943. Philippe de Clèves, Instruction du toutes manières. (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - St. Petersburg, (Former) Imperial Library. F. 11, 96. Le livre des fais d'armes et de chevalerie. (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Vienna, National Bibliothek. Photo Nr. M 966 62, Cod. 3430. Roman de la Mappemonde. Gautier de Mils, Image du monde. Christine de Pizan, La cité des dames, Le Livre des Trois Vertus. (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Compact disc with files from Willard's hard drive (all of the files are listed below on one disc, [use copies available]
    - Charity Willard autobiography
      - Emails involving corrections/adjustments with Charity and 2 other individuals (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Charity's autobiography, with selected bibliography of her works - includes commentary from publisher (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Original draft of Charity's autobiography (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Table of contents (Wommed) (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Charles V biography (by Christine de Pizan)
      - The first part of the Charles V Biography with footnotes (presumably added by Charity?); footnotes are only numbered but are not actually explained in this document (Box 3, Folder 42)
        - Charles V Biography sections 1 - 1 (11) with both footnotes and explanations (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Copy of above; in this copy, the text of the book is not in bold (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Charity's introduction to this edition of the biography (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Faits d'Armes (completed text)
      - Each section of the work is in an individual word file, with notes by Charity (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - 2 file versions of the complete work (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - File of Book 1 (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Chapter Master (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Index (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Introduction (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Introduction with notes on manuscripts (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Old E-mail Messages - several of Charity's old e-mails (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Outlook Contacts - Charity's e-mail address book (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Accountant Access Letter, giving her accountant permission to have access to her account (2004) (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Charity's review of a book of articles on Christine de Pizan by various scholars (Edited by Eric Hicks from 1998) (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Christine de Pizan - What appears to be the beginnings of a speech Charity wrote about Christine (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Preface to Christine's Vision (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Essay written by Charity relative to Christine's Vision entitled "For Christine's Vision" (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - A program that adds a cartoon cat to the desktop (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Essay: "Louise de la Tour, Dame de Crequy" (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Essay: "My Good Friend Christine de Pizan" (Box 3, Folder 42)
- SERIES VII. OVERSIZED MATERIALS
  - Writings (published)
    - Christine de Pizan: Her Life and Works, New York: Persea, 1985. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - The Book of Three Virtues (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Edition Critique of Les Faits d'armes et de chevalerie, by Christine de Pizan. Forthcoming. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Subject files
    - Photocopied books
      - Trans. Chaperon, Ian. Le Chemin de Long Estude de dame Cristine de Pise. Paris: Eltienne Groulteau, 1549. (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Nys, Ernest. L'Arbre des Batailles. Bruxelles et Leipzig: Merzvach & Falk, 1883 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Dissertations
    - Fernande Rosier, Madeleine (Sister Marie). Christine de Pisan as a Moralist. (2 vols.). (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - de Silva Nunes Ribeiro Cruzeiro, Maria Manuela. Espelho de Cristina: Estudo linguistico comparativo dos dois textos actualmente conhecidos de uma tradução medieval portuguesa do "Livre des Trois Vertus," de Christine de Pisan. (2 vols.). (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Book with Charity Cannon Willard's notes
    - Ringland Rains, Ruth. Les septes psaumes allégorisés of Christine de Pisan. Washington, D.C.,: Catholic University of America Press, 1965. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- BOOKS (by or containing writing by Charity Cannon Willard)
  - The Writings of Christine de Pizan. Edited by Charity Cannon Willard. New York: Persea, 1993. (Box 5)
  - The "Livre de la Paix" of Christine de Pizan: A Critical Edition with Introduction and Notes. The Hague: Mouton, 1958. (Box 5)
  - "The 'Three Virtues' of Christine de Pizan," in Boston Public Library Quarterly (1950): 201-305. (Box 5)
  - "A New Look at Christine de Pizan's Epistre au dieu d'Amours," in Beck, Jonathan and Mombello, Gianni. Seconda miscellanea di studi e ricerche sul quatttrocento francese. Chambéry et Turin, Centre d'études franco-italien. 1981. 71-92. (Box 5)
  - "Antoine de la Salle, Reader of Christine de Pizan," in McLeod, Glenda K. Visitors to the City: Readers of Christine Pizan. Lewiston, NY: Edward Mellen, 1991. (Box 5)
  - A Medieval Woman's Mirror of Honor: The Treasury of the City of Ladies ed. Madeleine Pelner Cosman. Translated by Charity Cannon Willard. New York: Persea, 1989. (Box 5)
  - Le Livre des trois vertus. Text established by Charity Cannon Willard in collaboration with Eric Hicks. Paris: Champion, 1989 (2 copies) (Box 5)
  - The Book of Arms and of Chivalry, by Christine de Pizan. Trans. B. G. Sumner Willard. Edited by Charity Cannon Willard. University Park, Penn.: Pennsylvania State University Press, 1999. (Box 5)
  - Christine de Pizan, Her Life and Works, by Charity Cannon Willard. New York: Persea, 1985 (2 copies). (Box 5)
  - Christine de Pizan: A Casebook. Foreword by Charity Cannon Willard. New York, NY: Routledge; 2003. xiii, pp. 296 (Box 5)
  - "Christine de Pizan on the Art of Warfare," in Desmond, Marilynn, ed. Christine de Pizan and the Categories of Difference. Minneapolis, MN: U of Minnesota P; 1998. pp. 3-15. xix, 287 pp. In Essays in Honor of L. F. Solano, ed. Raymond Cormier and Urban Holmes. Chapel Hill: University of North Carolina Press, 1970. (Box 5)
  - The Profane Arts of the Middle Ages: Commanding Women (issue in honor of Charity Cannon Willard). (Vol. VII, No. 2) (Autumn 1998). (Box 5)
  - "Christine de Pizan and the Order of the Rose," in Ideals for Women in the Works of Christine de Pizan, ed. Diane Bornstein. Michigan Consortium of Medieval and Early Modern Studies Monograph Series 1. 1981. (Box 5)
  - "Christine de Pizan: From Poet to Political Commentator," in Brabant, Margaret (ed.); Elshtain, Jean Bethke (introd.); Politics, Gender, and Genre: The Political Thought of Christine de Pizan. Boulder: Westview; 1992. pp. 17-32. xii, 240 pp. (Box 5)
  - "The Dominican Abbey of Poissy in 1400," in Campbell, John (ed. and preface); Margolis, Nadia (ed. and introd.); Christine de Pizan 2000. Amsterdam, Netherlands: Rodopi; 2000. pp. 209-18.429 pp. (Box 5)
  - Édition Critique of Le Livre de la paix, by Christine de Pizan. The Hague: Mouton, 1958. (Box 5)